A 60-minute Detective Conan Special!
!حلقة خاصة للمتحرّي كونان من 60 دقيقة
Today's case is a bit startling!
قضيّة اليوم مخيفة قليلاً
An impossible and illogical murder in a secluded mountain temple!
جريمة مستحيلة وغير منطقية !في معبد جبليّ معزول
The eerie legend of the Kiri Tengu...
...أسطورة تينغو الضباب المُهيبة
No matter how it's hidden, there's always only one truth!
!مهما أُخفيت، تبقى الحقيقة واحدة دوماً
"The Legendary Kiri Tengu Murders"
جرائم قتل أسطورة تينغو الضباب
Mountain cherry blossoms are so pretty!
أزهار الكرز الجبلية جميلة حقاً
Look, there are some on that mountain too!
انظرا، على ذاك الجبل أيضاً
The Someiyoshi cherry blossoms they have in the city aren't bad,
أزهار كرز سوميوشي لديهم في المدينة ليست سيّئة أيضاً
but the cherry blossom's true beauty is only found here in the wild,
لكنك تجد جمال أزهار الكرز الحقيقيّ في طبيعة الجبال فحسب
secluded away from civilization.
بعيداً عن مظاهر الحضارة
What a wet blanket...
...يا لفلسفتك
You say something?!
أقلت شيئاً؟
It was worth renting a car and coming all the way here, huh?!
استحقّ الأمر استئجار سيّارة والقدوم هنا، صحيح؟
For sure.
أجل
What do you say we take a picture?
ما رأيكم بأن نلتقط صورة؟
Here, you two stand over there!
قفا هناك
Let's go, Conan-kun!
هيّا بنا يا كونان-كن
Yeah!
أجل
Use the timer so you can get in the picture too!
!استعمل المؤقّت كي تتصوّر معنا يا أبي
Sure! Just a sec!
حسناً، انتظري قليلاً
My name is Conan Edogawa.
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
This is the would-be famous detective, Kogoro Mori.
هذا الرجل هو المتحرّي الذي سيشتهر، موري كوغورو
And this is my childhood friend and classmate, Ran Mori.
وهذه صديقة طفولتي وزميلتي، موري ران
Eh? How can she be my classmate?
ماذا؟ كيف تكون زميلتي؟
The truth is, I'm actually high school detective Shinichi Kudo.
في الحقيقة، أنا مُتحرٍّ في المدرسة الثانوية أُدعى كودو شينتشي
Yes. It all began on that day...
...أجل، بدأ كلّ شيء ذاك اليوم
I went to Tropical Land with Ran,
ذهبتُ إلى تروبيكال لاند مع ران
and there I witnessed a mysterious organization blackmailing someone.
وشهدتُ هناك ابتزاز منظمة غامضة لأحدهم
I watched Vodka, a man dressed in black,
كنتُ أشاهد فودكا، رجلاً برداء أسود
while Gin, another man in black, snuck up behind me.
بينما تسلّل ورائي جين، رجل آخر برداء أسود
I was knocked to the ground
وأطاحني بضربة
and forced to take a poison the organization had developed.
بعدها جعلني أتجرّع عقاراً طوّرته المنظمة
M-My body's burning up!
!جسمي ساخن
It's like my bones are melting!
!كأنّ... عظامي تذوب
I can't hold on!
!لا-لا أستطيع
When a police officer woke me up--
...عندما أيقظني ضابط شرطة
my body had shrunk!
!وجدتُ أنّ جسدي تقلّص
and get some of those pills!
!ثمّ أخذ ذاك العقار
Listen, Shinichi!
اسمع يا شينتشي
If they find out you're still alive,
،إن عرفوا أنّك لا تزال حيّاً
they'll come back to take care of you for good!
سيعودون للقضاء عليك
This must stay a secret between just the two of us!
!لذا أبقِ ما حصل سرّاً بيننا فقط
You mustn't tell anyone at all!
!إيّاك أن تخبر أحداً
That means not even Ran-kun!
!حتّى ران-كن بالطبع
This old man is Professor Agasa, an inventor.
هذا الرجل المُسن هو البروفسور أغاسا، مخترع
In my shrunken state, I became Conan Edogawa
وبعد تقلّص جسدي، غيّرت اسمي لإيدوغاوا كونان
and wound up living with Ran and her detective father,
وذهبتُ للعيش مع ران ووالدها المتحرّي
in the hopes of obtaining information about the men in black.
بأمل الحصول على معلومات عن الرجال بالرداء الأسود
But he's a horrible detective,
لكنّه كان متحرّياً فاشلاً
so I used the Professor's Anesthetic Watch Gun to put him to sleep
لذا استعملتُ ساعة اليد المخدّرة لتنويمه
and my Voice-Altering Bow Tie to solve all sorts of difficult cases.
ثمّ ربطة العنق المغيّرة للصوت لحلّ مختلف القضايا الصعبة
And that's my life as Conan so far.
وهكذا كانت حياتي للآن ككونان
When will I be able to turn back to normal?
متى سأرجع لجسدي الطبيعيّ يا ترى؟
Oh well. It'll happen when it happens!
!حسناً، سيحصل ذلك متى يحصل
Cheese!
!ابتسام
Well, we should head back.
حسناً، لنرجع
It looks like there's a shortcut up ahead, so let's take it.
يبدو أنّ هناك طريقاً مختصراً أمامنا، فلنسلكه
Are you sure about this, Dad? We're not going to get lost, are we?
أأنت متأكد يا أبي؟ ألن نضلّ؟
We'll be fine, don't worry!
!لا تقلقي، سيكون الأمر بخير
Let's get going.
هيّا بنا
See, I told you!
!كما أخبرتك! قلقي في محلّه
Now we're not only lost, but we have a flat tire too!
!لدينا إطار مثقوب فوق ضياعنا
Our fun trip's ruined now!
أُفسدت رحلتنا المسليّة الآن
Shut up!
اصمتي
Just what we need-- rain.
يأتي المطر ليزيد الطين بلّة
What now?!
ماذا سنفعل؟
It's twenty or thirty kilometers to the bottom of the mountain!
!لا نزال نبعد 20 إلى 30 كم عن أسفل الجيل
We have no other choice.
لا خيار لدينا
It doesn't look like anyone lives around here,
لا يبدو أنّ أحداً يعيش في القرب
so we'll have to spend the night in the car.
لذا علينا قضاء الليلة في السيّارة
I don't want to camp out in a place like this!
!لا أريد التخييم في مكان كهذا
Can't you fix the flat tire?!
ألا يمكنك إصلاح الإطار المثقوب؟
No spare.
لا إطار بديل لدينا
Two flat tires in one day-- talk about bad luck...
ثُقب إطاران في اليوم ذاته، يا للحظ السيّئ
Huh? Where'd he go?
ماذا؟ أين ذهب؟
Conan-kun?
كونان-كن؟
Where are you, Conan-kun?
أين أنت يا كونان-كن؟
What're you so worked up about?
لمَ الهلع؟
It was just a bird.
إنّها طيور فحسب
What is it, Ran? What was that scream?
ما الخطب يا ران-نيتشان؟ لمَ صرختِ للتو؟
What are you talking about?
ماذا؟ ما الذي تتكلم عنه؟
Anyway, where were you?!
بغض النظر عن ذلك، أين كنت؟
You shouldn't wander off on your own like that!
!لا يصحّ بك التجوّل بمفردك
I found a temple up ahead.
وجدتُ معبداً في الطريق هناك
I bet someone lives there!
لا بدّ أن أحداً يعيش في تلك الأنحاء
You're right, there is a temple there.
معك حق، يوجد معبد في مكان كهذا
We're saved!
!نجونا
Okay! Let's go check it out!
حسنٌ، لنذهب لتفقده
Yeah!
أجل
That's a really impressive place.
إنّه مبنيّ في مكان مُبهر بالفعل
Sandei Temple...
...معبد ساندي
It looks like our only option is to ask to stay the night...
يبدو أنّ خيارنا الوحيد المبيت هنا
Hello? Pardon the intrusion!
مرحباً؟ اعذرونا على التطفّل
Is anyone here?
أيوجد أحد؟
What do you want?
ما الذي تريدونه؟
I asked you what you want here!
سألتكم ماذا تريدون هنا؟
I take it you're from a newspaper or television station?
أيمكن أنّكم من صحيفة أو محطّة تلفازية؟
Leave!
!ارحلوا
This place is not meant for uncouth vermin such as yourselves!
!ليس هذا مكاناً لمتطفلين فظّين مثلكم
No, we were just passing by when we got a flat tire.
كلا، كنا نعبر بالجوار عندما ثُقِب إطارنا
We were wondering if we could stay here for the night...
...وخطر لنا أن نسألكم لو يمكننا المبيت الليلة هنا
What? You want to stay here?!
!ماذا؟ تريدون المبيت هنا؟
Yes...
...أجل
But if that's a problem, we'll leave right away--
...لكن إن كانت مشكلةً، فسنغادر فوراً
Oh! Why didn't you say so sooner?!
!هكذا إذاً! كان عليك أن تقول قبلاً
I had you pegged as reporters who came here about the incident...
...ظننتكم صحفيّين أتوا للسؤال عن تلك الحادثة
"The incident"?
أيّ حادثة؟
Oh, nothing of importance.
لا شيء مهم
One night plus vegetarian meals is 10,000 yen per adult
سيكلّف مبيت ليلة زائد وجبات نباتيّة عشرة آلاف ينّ للبالغ
and 8,000 yen per child.
وثمانية آلاف للطفل
This temple also serves as a small inn...
...هذا المعبد يمثّل نُزلاً صغيراً أيضاً
10,000 yen?!
!عشرة آلاف ين؟
Take it or leave it.
اقبل أو ارفض
It's six hours to the bottom of the mountain.
تستغرق المسافة 6 ساعات لأسفل الجبل
Walk if you'd like.
امش إذا أردت
I haven't said no yet...
لم أرفض بعد
I see.
حسناً
Hey, we have our first guests in a long time!
!اسمعوا، لدينا ضيوف بعد وقت طويل
Wait!
!ا-انتظر
I haven't said yes yet, either...
...لم أقل أنّي سأقبل أيضاً
Take my advice. Stay the night.
خذ نصيحتي، بِت هنا
On rainy nights such as tonight,
ففي ليال ممطرة كالليلة
there's no way to know where it may be lurking...
لا تعرف أين قد يختبئ
"It"?
قد يختبئ؟
Is there a bear out there?
أيوجد دب في الجوار؟
A bear?
دب؟
It's not nearly as adorable, I'm afraid...
...ليس شيئاً بتلك الظرافة
No, I refer to an ancient beast that prefers rain and darkness
أقصد الوحش القديم الذي يُحب المطر والظلام
and devours people's souls...
ويلتهم أرواح الناس
The Kiri Tengu!
!تينغو الضباب
The Kiri Tengu?!
تـ-تينغو الضباب؟
What am I thinking?! That name is taboo here!
!ما الذي أفعله؟! هذا الاسم محظور هنا
Forget what I just said!
!انسوا ما قلتُه
Oh, here you are.
ها أنتم
Allow me to introduce you to the four priests-in-training at this temple.
دعوني أقدّم لكم الرهبان الأربعة قيد التمرين في هذا المعبد
This is Kannen. He has been here the longest and is like an older brother to the others.
هذا كانّين، أقدم الأربعة هنا وأشبه بالأخ الكبير للبقيّة
Pleased to meet you!
!سُررت بلقائكم
This is Tonnen. He may eat a lot, but he's a great cook and strong, too.
هذا تونّين، شره قليلاً لكنّه طاهٍ بارع وقويّ البنية أيضاً
This is Mokunen. We leave all the carpentry work to him and his dexterous fingers.
هذا موكونين، نترك كلّ أعمال التجارة له لحرفيّته وبراعة يديه
It's nice to meet you!
يسرّني لقاؤكم
This here is Shunen. He came to our temple just this year
هذا شونين، أتى لمعبدنا هذا العام
and although he's a bit timid, his passion for studying is unrivaled.
رغم أنه خجول، لكنه مُجتهد في الدراسة وحاد الذهن
Hello.
مرحباً
And I'm Tenei-- the head priest of this temple.
وأنا تيني، الراهب الأكبر لهذا المعبد
Tonnen and Mokunen, prepare our dinner.
تونّين وموكونين، فلتحضّرا العشاء
Kannen and Shunen, show our guests around the temple.
بينما ليرشد كانّين وشونين ضيوفنا داخل المعبد
Understood!
!حاضر
Looks like we're staying.
يبدو أنّنا سنبيت
Darn it!
تبّاً
With the late fee on the rental car and the cost to stay here,
بأجر تأخير السيّارة المستأجرة وتكلفة البقاء هنا
I won't have any money for booze this month!
لن أملك مالاً للساكي هذا الشهر
This is Sandei Temple's main hall.
هذه ردهة معبد ساندي الأساسية
It certainly is impressive.
مُبهرة بحق
What do you say to having your own funeral services here?
ما رأيك بإقامة شعائر جنازتك هنا؟
Just kidding!
!أمزح فحسب
Lousy priest...
...يا إلهي
This way, if you would...
من هنا إذاً
Huh? Why does that room have a lock on it?
ماذا؟ لمَ يوجد قفل على تلك الغرفة؟
Empty...
...فارغة
Wait, little boy! That's--
...يا فتى، تلك
It's just a small room...
...مجرّد غرفة صغيرة
Little boy!
!أيّها الفتى
That's one tall ceiling!
!سقف عالٍ
What is this room?
ما هذه الغرفة أيّها الراهب؟
What is it?
أخبرنا... أيّها الراهب؟
Our meditation room.
غرفة تأملّنا
They used to lock priests in here who broke religious precepts
كانوا يحتجزون الرهبان الذين خرقوا المبادئ العقائدية هنا سابقاً
to make them reflect on their mistakes.
لجعلهم يراجعون أخطاءهم
No wonder it's built so solidly...
...لا عجب أنّها بُنيت بهذه الصلابة
And they covered the room with lacquer to prevent climbing out...
كما غطّوا جدران الغرفة بطلاء اللَّك لمنع التسلّق
Say, why does this part of the wall have a different color?
أخبرني، لمَ لون هذا الجانب مختلف؟
Mokunen-san fixed that after it was broken during the incident.
لأنّ موكونين-سان أصلحه بعدما حُطّم في تلك الحادثة
Isn't that right, Kannen-san?
أليس كذلك يا كانّين-سان؟
What incident?
أيّ حادثة؟
It happened before I came to this temple,
وقعت قبل قدومي لهذا المعبد
so I don't know the details.
فلا أعرف التفاصيل
--But apparently the Kiri Tengu-- --That's enough, Shunen!
...لكن يبدو أنّ تينغو الضباب
Our visitors don't need to hear about it!
!لا داعي لتثقل على ضيوفنا بذلك
Sorry...
...آسف
Huh? What's that sound?
ماذا؟ ما هذا الصوت؟
The waterfall.
الشلّال
Would you like to see it?
هل تريدين رؤيته؟
It's right next to this room!
إنّه بجوار هذه الغرفة
Conan-kun! Hurry up!
!كونان-كن! أسرع
Okay!
!حاضر
Wow! The waterfall's so close!
!مُذهل! الشلّال قريب جدّاً
Amazing!
!مُبهر
Look! Some of the water's even flowing over the handrail!
انظروا، بعضٌ من ماء الشلّال !ينهمر فوق الحاجز
Careful, now.
توخّوا الحذر
While there is a drainboard there,
لدينا لوح تصريف
you don't want to slip and fall.
لكن هناك خطر الانزلاق
Yes. They fall down from the cherry trees above.
بلى، سقطت من أشجار الكرز في الأعلى وجرفها الماء
Elegant, isn't it?
جميل بحقّ
Let's go back.
لنرجع
Dinner should be ready by now.
يُفترض أنّ العشاء قد جهز
Priests have an image of being stiff,
يُعرف عن الرهبان تشددهم
but you actually have lots of time to have fun!
!لكن لديكم وقت للاستمتاع
Yeah! Sometimes we even go to the beach during our breaks!
أجل، نذهب أحياناً وقت عطلتنا للشاطئ حتّى
We take out the temple's inflatable boat and beach ball...
نأخذ طوف المعبد القابل للنفخ وكرة شاطئ
And the head priest is quite fond of girls in bikinis!
والراهب الأكبر مُعجب بالفتيات بلباس السباحة
That's enough.
!لا داعي لذكر ذلك
Say, I've been wondering about it for a while,
هناك ما يحيّرني منذ مدّة
but what's the Kiri Tengu?
ما هو تينغو الضباب؟
Where did you hear that name?!
!أ-أين سمعت الاسم يا فتى؟
Forgive me. I allowed my mouth to get ahead of myself.
آسف، زلّ لساني
Head Priest!
!الراهب الأكبر
It's just an absurd old tale.
إنّها مجرد حكاية قديمة سخيفة
On rainy nights, the ancient Tengu creeps into the village
في الليالي الممطرة، يتسلّل تينغو كالسراب للقريّة
and uses its tremendous strength to smash into houses
ويستعمل قوّته الهائلة لتحطيم المنازل
and kidnap their inhabitants.
واختطاف سكّانهم
It soars to the top of tall trees,
ثم يحلّق لقمّة شجرة عالية
hangs the corpses, and devours their flesh!
!يعلّق الجثث ويأكل لحمها
He kidnaps only young girls who have tender meat!
!يختطف الفتيات الشابات بلحم طريّ فحسب
Yes, girls just like you...
أجل، فتيات مثلك تماماً
But it's just a legend, don't take it seriously!
لكنّها مجرد أسطورة من الماضي، لا تأخذيها بجديّة
You heard him.
كما سمعتِه
But...
...لكن
But it's not just a story...
...لكنّها ليست مجرد حكاية
There was an eerie incident just like that, two years ago...
...وقعت حادثة مريبة شبيهة بها قبل عامين
Mokunen!
!موكونين
Say, why don't you ask them the details about that incident!
لمَ لا تسألهم عن تفاصيل القضيّة يا عمّ؟
After all, you are Kogoro Mori, Great Detective!
!فأنت المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو
You might find something out!
قد تكتشف شيئاً
The great detective?!
!المتحرّي العظيم؟
--Mori?! - -Mori?!
!موري؟
--Kogoro?! - -Kogoro?!
!كوغورو؟
You're famous!
!أنت ذاك المتحرّي الشهير
Only you could ever solve that difficult case!
!أنت الوحيد القادر على حلّ تلك القضية الصعبة
Please listen, Detective!
...اسمع سيّدي المتحرّي
Two years ago, a young priest--
...قبل عامين، كان هناك راهب شاب
Silence!
!يكفي
Have you forgotten our promise to never speak of that incident again?!
أنسيتم وعدنا بعدم الكلام عن تلك الحادثة مُجدداً؟
But Head Priest!
!لـ-لكن سيّدي الراهب الأكبر
Dinner is over!
انتهى العشاء
Detective. I will let you stay the night,
،حضرة المتحرّي، سأسمح لكم بالمبيت
but I want you to leave the temple early tomorrow morning.
لكن عليكم مغادرة المعبد في الصباح الباكر
Don't take it personally.
لا تعتبر الأمر شخصياً
Okay...
حـ-حسناً
Dad.
أبي
Tengus aren't real, are they?
تينغو ليس حقيقيّاً، صحيح؟
Obviously not.
بالطبع
Do you really think kappa and oni really exist?
أتظنّين الكابّا والأوني متواجدين حقّاً؟
Tengus are the same-- imaginary creatures invented by people.
تينغو مثلهم، مخلوق من مخيلة البشر
I guess you're right...
لعلّك مُحق
Actually, the ancient Chinese
في الصين القديمة، كانوا يشيرون للشُهب
referred to shooting stars that made loud, thunder-like sounds
التي تصدر صوتاً عالياً شبيهاً بالرعد
as "Heavenly Dogs," or Tengu, thus the name.
بالكلاب السماوية، أو "تينغو"، ومنه الاسم
In China, such shooting stars were considered unlucky omens.
كانت تعتبر تلك الشهب نذير حظّ سيّئ في الصين
Those beliefs came to Japan,
انتقلت تلك المعتقدات لليابان
and Tengus changed from strange phenomenon to strange monsters!
وتغيّر تينغو من ظاهرة غريبة لوحش غريب
For a little runt you sure know lots of weird things.
تعرف الكثير من الأشياء الغريبة بالنسبة لطفل
I, uh, saw it on a TV show the other day...
...كـ-كان ذلك على التلفاز في ذاك اليوم
So there's nothing to be afraid of, Ran!
لذا لا شيء لتخافيه يا ران-نيتشان
Don't be silly, I'm not afraid of anything!
!لا تكن سخيفاً، لم أخف شيئاً
Well, let's get some sleep.
هيّا، لننم
Conan-kun.
كونان-كن
If you get scared during the night, you can come sleep with me!
إذا شعرت بالخوف ليلاً، يمكنك القدوم للنوم معي
Nighty night!
!عُمتما مساءً
Hey, now.
...أنت
Listen, Conan-kun.
اسمع يا كونان-كن
If you get scared during the night, you can come sleep with me!
إذا شعرت بالخوف ليلاً، يمكنك القدوم للنوم معي
He kidnaps only young girls who have tender meat!
يختطف الفتيات الشابات بلحم طريّ فحسب
Yes, girls just like you...
أجل، فتيات مثلك تماماً
Stupid Ran, waking us up in the middle of the night!
ران تلك، أيقظتنا في منتصف الليل
What's the big deal?! I can't help that I'm a scaredy-cat!
!ما بكما؟ لا يسعني فعل شيء إن كنت سريعة الخوف
Hey, what do you think that incident was?
ما كانت تلك الحادثة برأيك؟
Heck if I know.
كيف لي أن أعرف
He doesn't want to talk about it, so it's best not to ask.
لا يريد الكلام عنها، فيجدر بنا ألّا نسأل
As if the Kiri Tengu would actually appear...
...لا يمكن أنّ تينغو الضباب ظهر حقّاً
Oh?
ماذا؟
What is this about me?
ماذا قلت عني؟
See! You're a scaredy-cat too!
!رأيتما؟ أنتما جبانان أيضاً
Ran! Where'd you get that mask?!
ر-ران! من أين حصلتِ على هذا القناع؟
It was hanging in the bathroom.
كان معلّقاً في دورة المياه
Why you...
...أ-أنت
What happened?!
!ماذا حصل؟
Nothing...
...لا-لا شيء
Good night, Kannen-san!
!عُمت مساءً يا كانّين-سان
Pleasant dreams!
!نَم جيّداً
I shouldn't have brought this! Now what do I do?
انتهى بي المطاف بأخذ هذا معي، ما العمل؟
You shouldn't have put it on in the first place!
!يا إلهي، لم يكن عليك ارتداؤه بدايةً
Now I'm wide awake.
طار النوم من عينيّ الآن
Breakfast is ready.
الإفطار جاهز يا سادة
Okay! We'll be there soon!
حسناً، سنأتي فوراً
You look pretty tired, Shunen-san...
يبدو أنّك لم تنم جيّداً يا شونين-سان
Yes. I was up late last night reading...
صحيح، سهرتُ البارحة بالقراءة
Please excuse me.
اعذروني
You didn't get much sleep either, Mokunen-san?
يبدو أنّك لم تنم كفايتك أيضاً يا موكونين-سان
No thanks to your screaming!
!بسبب صراخك
I couldn't get any sleep after that!
!لم أستطع النوم قلقاً بعده
Sorry...
...آسف
But that's nothing compared to Tonnen, he hasn't slept at all.
لكنّ ذلك لا يُقارن بتونّين الذي لم يغمض له جفن
Where are the head priest and Kannen-san?
أين الراهب الأكبر وكانّين-سان؟
We haven't seen the head priest, so Kannen went to look for him...
لم نرَ الراهب الأكبر، لذا ذهب كانّين للبحث عنه
He's probably in a room somewhere downing some sake--
...إنّه في إحدى الغرف على الأرجح غارق في الشراب
That was Kannen's voice!
!ذاك صوت كانّين
It sounded like it came from the meditation room!
!بدا أنّه من غرفة التأمّل
What is it?!
ما الخطب؟
Up there!
!هـ-هناك
Head Priest Tenei!
!الراهب الأكبر تينّي
The victim was this temple's head priest, Tenei.
كان الضحيّة المشنوق الراهب الأكبر لهذا المعبد، تينّي
He died approximately between 10:00 pm and 12:00 am last night.
وقت الموت المقدّر بين العاشرة ومنتصف الليل البارحة
And you were the one who found his body.
وكنتَ من وجد الجثّة أيّها الراهب المتدرّب
Correct, Kannen-san?
صحيح يا كانّين-سان؟
Yes.
أجل
We didn't see him this morning, so I went to look for him.
لم نره هذا الصباح، لذا ذهبتُ للبحث عنه
And then I found him in this meditation room...
...ثمّ وجدته في غرفة التأمّل هكذا
And by yet another strange coincidence,
،وبمصادفة غريبة أخرى
the person who rushed here after the scream was--
...الشخص الذي هرع هنا بعد سماعه الصرخة كان
But that was one extraordinary scream, Kannen-san!
كانت تلك صرخةً مبهرة بحقّ يا كانّين-سان
Not nearly as extraordinary as yours!
!ليس بقدر صرختك
You have really keen senses, don't you, Kannen-san?
لديك حواس حادّة حقّاً يا كانّين-سان
After all, the head priest was hanging all the way up there.
فالراهب الأكبر كان متدلياً من أعلى السقف هناك
If it were me, I probably wouldn't have seen him right away...
لو كنتُ أنا، لما وجدته فوراً على الأغلب
That is strange, Kannen-san.
هذا غريب بالفعل يا كانّين-سان
You didn't happen to already know
لم تعلم أنّه متدلٍّ
Nothing of the sort! I just--
...بـ-بلا مزاح! كنتُ فقط
It was only natural for him to find it.
من الطبيعيّ أن يجده
The exact same thing happened in this room two years ago...
فالأمر نفسه وقع قبل عامين في هذه الغرفة
Two years ago?!
قبل عامين؟
Yes. I was in charge of that case too.
أجل، كنتُ المسؤول عن تلك القضيّة أيضاً
I believe the one who died was a priest-in-training named Chunen.
أظنّ الضحيّة كان راهباً قيد التمرين يُدعى تشونين
And it was Kannen-san and Mokunen-san who found the body, right?
وكان كانّين-سان وموكونين-سان من وجدا الجثّة، صحيح؟
Yes.
أجل
It happened during the rainy season...
وقع ذلك أثناء موسم المطر
After coming into this room to meditate,
،بعد قدومه لهذه الغرفة للتأمّل
Chunen tore a big hole in the wall and disappeared.
أحدث تشونين-سان فجوةً كبيرة في الحائط واختفى
We looked for three days and three nights,
،بحثنا عنه لثلاثة أيام بلياليها
but he was nowhere to be found.
لكن لم نجده
We assumed he had fled the temple,
،افترضنا أنّه هرب من المعبد
and on the morning of the 4th day,
،ثمّ في صباح اليوم الرابع
I came into this room with Kannen to fix the wall.
أتيتُ لهذه الغرفة مع كانّين لإصلاح الحائط
When we happened to glance upward...
...وعندما نظرنا للأعلى
...there was Chunen-san, hanging from the ceiling!
!وجدنا تشونين-سان مشنوقاً من السقف
Is this hole the same place that was broken last time?
أهذه الفجوة بنفس مكان الحادثة السابقة؟
Yes.
أجل
At first, we thought that Chunen-san made it to escape,
اعتقدنا أنّ تشونين-سان أحدثها للهرب بدايةً
but the door to this room wasn't locked,
لكنّ باب الغرفة لم يكن مقفلاً
and a local carpenter who came to fix the outer wall
وقال نجّار محليّ أتى لإصلاح الحائط الخارجي
said it would take an entire day for a person to make a hole that big!
أنّ فتح فجوة بهذا الحجم سيستغرق يوماً كاملاً بالنسبة لفرد
Ridiculous. There's no such thing.
سخافة، لا وجود لشيء كذاك
Inspector!
!حضرة المفتّش
It really is exactly like two years ago.
إنّها كالحادثة قبل عامين فعلاً
The two side beams are covered in dust,
الغبار يغطّي العارضتين الجانبيتين
and there are no signs of anything touching them.
ولا آثار للمس شيء لهما
A bit of dust has been knocked off the middle beam,
أُزيح جزء من الغبار عن العارضة الوسطى
but that's because of the rope tied to it.
لكنّ ذلك بسبب الحبل المربوط بها
There are no rub marks to indicate he was hoisted up.
لا آثار احتكاك تشير إلى أنّه رُفع
Do you suppose this was a suicide too?
ربما كان انتحاراً أيضاً هذه المرّة
Suicide?
انتحار؟
Yeah, you can manage to get up there
أجل، يمكنك الصعود هناك
if you climb across the beams and use rope like that officer,
إذا تسلّقت العارضتين واستعملت الحبل كما فعل الشرطيّ
but it's a different story if you're trying to carry someone up there.
لكنّ حمل شخص إلى هناك موضوع مختلف
The late priest Chunen and the head priest weren't all that small.
الراهب المُتوفى تشونين والراهب الأكبر لم يكونا صغيري البنية
Scaling the rope with them tied to your back would be nigh impossible.
تسلّق الحبل وهما على ظهرك أشبه بالمستحيل
If you tied the noose around their necks and hoisted them up,
إذا ربطت العقدة بعنقهما ورفعتهما
it would leave marks on the beam.
ستكون هناك آثار على العارضة
Someone could have climbed up first and then pulled them up,
يمكن أنّ شخصاً صعد بدايةً وسحب الضحيّة
but that narrow beam is the only place to stand,
لكنّ الموطئ الوحيد هي تلك العارضة الضيّقة
so it's extremely unlikely.
فالأمر غير مُحتمل
Which means they must have climbed the ropes themselves,
ما يعني أنّهما صعدا الحبل بنفسيهما
made a noose while on the beam,
وشكّلا عقدة على العارضة
and then jumped off with the noose around their necks.
ثمّ قفزا بالعقدة حول عنقيهما
Some leftover rope and an axe probably used to cut it
وجدنا على الأرض بقايا حبل
were found on the ground,
كما فأس اُستعمل لقطعه غالباً
so it would seem that was the case.
فيبدو أنّ هذا ما حصل
But what has me wondering is that hole in the wall...
لكن ما يحيّرني هو الفجوة في الحائط
...it's exactly like last time!
المماثلة للسابقة
I don't know how they broke the wall,
لا أعرف كيف حطّما الحائط
but they probably broke it and hanged themselves from a tall ceiling
لكنّهما فعلا ذلك وشنقا نفسيهما من السقف المرتفع
to make it look like that old legend.
لتقليد تلك الأسطورة القديمة غالباً
Almost as if to suggest to us
كأنّهما يريدان إخبارنا
that they were attacked by the flying Kiri Tengu.
أنّ تينغو الضباب الطائر هاجمهما
That ridiculous tale sends everyone in a panic...
تلك الحكاية السخيفة تنشر الهلع في الناس
But doesn't this broken wall seem strange?
لكن ألا يبدو هذا الحائط المُحطم غريباً؟
There was a sliding panel here, right?
كانت توجد نافذة صغيرة هنا، صحيح؟
Yeah...
أجل
For such a big hole in the wall, there's almost no debris left.
بالكاد توجد أيّ آثار حطام بالنسبة لفجوة بهذا الحجم
That's true...
معك حق
They probably threw them over.
أسقطها غالباً
After all, these people did make their suicides
فقد أقدم على الانتحار بأسلوب
look like the Kiri Tengu's doing.
يجعلنا نعتقد أنّه كان تينغو الضباب
Who knows what they were thinking.
لا تعرف ما الذي جال برأسه
Grandpa!
!جدّي
Grandpa! Grandpa!
!جدّي! جدّي
Oh? Isn't she--
...ماذا؟ أليست تلك
The head priest's granddaughter, Kikuno-san.
حفيدة الراهب الأكبر، كيكونو-سان
Grandpa! Why did this happen?!
!جدّي! لمَ حصل هذا؟
She cried two years ago too, when she saw Priest Chunen's body...
بكت قبل عامين عندما رأت جثّة الراهب تشونين أيضاً
Yes. She used to visit on occasion back then,
أجل، كانت تزور المعبد على فترات في السابق
but she suddenly stopped coming after the incident...
لكنّها توقّفت عن القدوم بعد تلك الحادثة
Grandpa! Grandpa!
!جدّي! جدّي
Who's he?
من هو؟
Kikuno-san's husband.
إنّه زوج كيكونو-سان
They married only a few days ago.
تزوّجا قبل بضعة أيام
I hear he's the successor to a big temple
سمعت أنّه خليفة معبد كبير
and the two of them were arranged to be married since they were little.
وكان زواجهما منسّقاً منذ صغرهما
I was really shocked when I heard that from the head priest two years ago.
صُدمت عندما سمعت بذلك قبل عامين من الراهب الأكبر
I had always thought that she and Chunen-san were to be together.
لطالما اعتقدت أنّ تشونين-سان وكيكونو-سان سيكونان معاً
The late Chunen-san?
تشونين-سان الراحل؟
Yes.
أجل
The two were so close they seemed like real brother and sister.
كانا مقرّبين بحيث بدوا كشقيقين
It must have been a real shock to Chunen-san
لا بدّ أنّ الخبر نزل على تشونين-سان كالصاعقة
when he heard she was going to be married.
عندما سمع بزواج كيكونو-سان
That's probably why he did that foolish thing...
لذا أقدم على تلك الحماقة
Maybe the head priest had been worrying about that this whole time--
...ربما كان الراهب الأكبر متضايقاً من ذاك الأمر
...and killed himself like Chunen-san
وقتل نفسه مثل تشونين-سان
mere days after Kikuno-san's wedding!
!بعد بضعة أيام من زواج كيكونو-سان
That is a possibility...
هذا مُحتمل فعلاً
If so, then there should be a will somewhere.
يُفترض أن تكون هناك وصيّة في مكانٍ ما إذاً
Then let's all split up and look for it!
لننفصل جميعاً ونبحث عنها
Suicide?!
انتحار؟
Are you so sure?
أحقّاً ذلك؟
No matter how much it looks like the old legend,
مهما بدت كأسطورة قديمة
would anybody really hang themselves from a place like that?!
هل يشنق أحد نفسه من مكان كذاك حقّاً؟
And would they really make such a big hole on purpose?!
كما هل يتكبّد فتح فجوة بذاك الحجم؟
What if it wasn't a suicide
إذا لم يكن انتحاراً
and this big hole was used for some sort of trick...
...واُستعملت هذه الفجوة الكبيرة لحيلة ما
This incident and the one two years ago were pulled off the same way.
فنُفذت هذه الحادثة وسابقتها قبل عامين بنفس الطريقة
Meaning Chunen and the head priest were murdered by the same person.
أي أنّ تشونين والراهب الأكبر قُتلا على يد نفس الشخص
What are you doing, little boy?
ما الذي تفعله يا فتى؟
Shunen-san!
شونين-سان
Come to think of it, this guy said he came to this temple one year ago.
بالمناسبة، قال أنّه أتى لهذا المعبد قبل عام
I doubt he could've made that big hole with these scrawny arms...
لا أظنّه سيفتح فجوةً بذاك الحجم بهذه الذراع الهزيلة
Say, you said you were up late last night reading a book, right?
قلتَ أنّك كنت تسهر بالقراءة البارحة، صحيح؟
Did you notice anything strange during that time?
هل لاحظت شيئاً غريباً ذاك الوقت؟
Like anyone sneaking out of their room,
مثل تسلّل أحد خارج غرفته
or an eerie sound from something breaking,
أو صوت غريب لتحطّم شيء
or anyone screaming?!
!أو صراخ أحد؟
No, I didn't hear anything.
كلا، لم أسمع شيئاً
You really heard nothing?
لم تسمع شيئاً حقّاً؟
The head priest's room is a little ways away,
غرفة الراهب الأكبر بعيدة
but everyone's sleeping quarters are next to each other,
لكنّ غرف نوم الجميع بجوار بعضها
so we'd know right away if anything happened.
لذا سنعرف فوراً إن حصل شيء
Don't tell me you're suspicious of everyone?
أيمكن أنّك تشتبه بالجميع؟
Not really...
..ليس تماماً
Hey, Shunen!
!شونين
Stop lounging around and help us look!
!كفّ عن التخاذل وساعدنا في البحث
Oh, right!
!حـ-حاضر
Alright, just a little more!
!حسناً، القليل فقط
You freaked me out when you started to lose your grip there!
!أخفتني عندما بدأت قبضتك تضعف
Sorry 'bout that!
آسف
Hey, officers!
!حضرات الضبّاط
That's the window at the top of the room
هذه النافذة فوق الغرفة
where the head priest died, right?
التي مات فيها الراهب الأكبر، صحيح؟
Yeah...
أ-أجل
You can't carry someone through here onto the middle beam?
لا يمكنك نقل شخص هنا فوق العارضة الوسطى؟
Conan-kun! Where are you?
كونان-كن! أين أنت؟
If you're looking for that boy,
،إن كنتِ تبحثين عن ذاك الفتى
he asked how to get to the woods below the temple
فقد سأل عن كيفية الذهاب للغابة
and then left.
أسفل المعبد وغادر
The only things missing from the scene
الشيء الوحيد المفقود
were the fragments from that broken wall!
!هو آثار ذاك الجزء المحطم من الحائط
If the killer threw them over the side,
لو رماها القاتل من هناك حقّاً
they would have landed around here somewhere!
فيُفترض أنّها سقطت في الأرجاء
If I can find them,
إذا وجدتُها قد أعرف السبب
I might figure out the reason the killer had to get rid of them!
!الذي دفع القاتل للتخلّص منها
Bingo! A piece of the wood!
!ها هي! قطعة خشب
This was part of that sliding panel...
...هذا جزء من النافذة الصغيرة
There's tape on it... What for?
...يوجد شريط لاصق
What are you doing down here?!
!ولد! ما الذي تفعله هنا؟
Ran!
!ران-نيتشان
What's with that dirty piece of wood?!
ما قطعة الخشب القذرة هذه؟
Get rid of it!
!ارمها
I can't!
!لا يمكنني
Alright! Let's call it a day!
حسناً، لننصرف الآن
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
Say, where's Kikuno-san?
أين كيكونو-سان؟
She went with the body to the police headquarters.
ذهبت مع الجثّة لمركز الشرطة
But we can't seem to find his will.
لكننا لم نجد الوصيّة في النهاية
That's okay. At least we know it was a suicide...
لا بأس، عرفنا أنّه انتحار على الأقل
No! It was a murder!
!كلا، كانت جريمة قتل
Something happened in this room last night!
وقع شيءٌ ما في هذه الغرفة البارحة
Something beyond imagination!
!شيء يفوق التصوّر
The wall which was destroyed by an immense strength...
...الحائط الذي حُطّم بقوّة هائلة
The warped cut on the drainboard...
...أثر القطع المعوج على لوح التصريف
And the dumped piece of wood from the wall
وقطعة الخشب من النافذة المرميّة من الحائط
and the tape that was stuck to it...
والشريط اللاصق عليها
What is the key that connects them all?
ما المفتاح الذي يربطها كلّها؟
That's it! I've figured out the killer's trick!
!هكذا إذاً! اكتشفت الحيلة التي استعملها القاتل
If that's the case, then the killer must've spent the entire night in this room...
في تلك الحالة، لا بدّ أنّ القاتل أمضى الليلة بأسرها في هذه الغرفة
Ah! So that's why he said that!
!فهمت، لذا قال ذلك
He's the killer, no question about it!
يبدو أنّ المجرم هو ذاك الشخص بلا شكّ
The impossible crime...
...الجريمة المستحيلة
...a work of foul art created at the scene of the crime by a murderer.
إنّه عمل فنّي شرير يرسمه القاتل في مسرح الجريمة
The piece of art exhibited this time
القطعة الفنّية المعروضة هذه المرّة
was a room in a mountain temple where the cherry blossoms fall.
هي غرفة في معبد جبليّ تتساقط عليه أزهار الكرز
Someone murdered the temple's head priest
قتل أحدهم الراهب الأكبر للمعبد
by tying him to an elevated beam and then hanging him!
بربطه على عارضة مرتفعة ثمّ شنقه
Naturally, there were no marks of him being pulled up.
لم تكن هناك آثار على سحبه بطبيعة الأمر
It seems utterly impossible for a human to commit this crime...
فبدا أنّها جريمة مستحيلة على البشر
Yes, the killer utilized a certain technique to float in the air!
!أجل، استعمل القاتل تقنيةً ما للتحليق في الهواء
Just like the adroit flying Kiri Tengu!
!كتينغو الضباب الطائر واسع المهارة
Some unused rope and an axe lay on the floor
وجدنا حبلاً غير مُستعمل وفأساً على أرض الغرفة
of the room where the head priest was killed.
التي قُتل فيها الراهب الأكبر
But the strangest thing of all
لكنّ أكثر الأشياء غرابة
was that although there was a huge hole in the wall,
هو عدم وجود آثار حطام للفجوة الكبيرة
there was no debris from it.
التي كانت في الحائط
Then there was the drainboard with the warped cut,
ثم هناك لوح التصريف بأثر القطع المعوّج
and the piece of wood from the sliding panel
وقطعة الخشب من النافذة الصغيرة في الغابة
and the tape that was on it...
كما الشريط اللاصق عليها
What is the key that connects them all?
ما المفتاح الذي يربطها كلّها؟
A cherry blossom?
زهرة كرز؟
That's it! I've figured out the killer's trick!
!هكذا إذاً! اكتشفت الحيلة التي استعملها القاتل
If that's the case,
في تلك الحالة، لا بدّ أنّ القاتل
then the killer must've spent the entire night in this room!
أمضى الليلة بأسرها في هذه الغرفة
Ah! So that's why he said that!
!فهمت، لذا قال ذلك
He's the killer, no question about it!
!إنّه القاتل بلا شك
Please, Inspector Megure?
!أرجوك سيّدي المفتش
Alright, alright.
حسناً، حسناً
I'll take you home in my patrol car.
سآخذك للمنزل بسيّارة الشرطة
I have to make them notice before everyone leaves...
حسناً، عليّ إعلامهم قبل مغادرة الشرطة
Hand over the keys to the rental car
أعطني مفتاح سيّارتك المستأجرة
that just happened to get a flat tire in the forest!
التي ثُقب إطارها في الغابة
I'll have one of my men return it for you.
سأجعل أحد رجالي يرجعها لك
We owe a great deal to your detective skills, after all.
فأنت تساعدنا باستنتاجاتك دوماً
Thanks a bunch!
!شكراً جزيلاً
I got the keys!
!حصلتُ على المفتاح
Get back here, kid!
!ارجع يا ولد
Damn it, where'd that brat go?!
!تبّاً، أين ذهب ذاك الفتى؟
No drainboards!
!لا ألواح تصريف
Oops, he slipped and knocked himself out...
...انزلق وأفقد وعيه بنفسه
Oh well.
حسناً، لا يهم
Now I don't have to use the Anesthetic Watch Gun on him!
ليس عليّ استعمال الساعة المخدّرة الآن
This button acts as a tiny wireless speaker.
بهذا الزرّ وظيفة مكبّر صوت لاسلكيّ صغير
Whatever you say into your bow tie will come out of this.
أيّ ما تقوله في سمّاعة ربطة عنق سيخرج منه
I'll just stick this here...
...سألصقه هنا
Hey, little boy!
!يا فتى
Officer!
!حضرة الشرطيّ
You shouldn't come in here without permission.
عليك ألّا تدخل هنا دون إذن
Perfect timing!
!توقيت ممتاز
Mori-san said he wants everyone to gather in the room
قال العمّ موري أنّه يريدك أن تجمع الآخرين
where the incident happened!
!في غرفة وقوع الحادثة
And do you have any tape?
كما ألديك شريط لاصق؟
Tape?
شريط لاصق؟
What? You know who did it?!
!ماذا؟ عرفت هويّة المجرم؟
Yes.
أجل
I know who killed the head priest and made it look like a suicide.
أعرف من قتل الراهب الأكبر وجعله يبدو انتحاراً
Hey, now.
مهلك
The head priest died after he was tied to an elevated beam
مات الراهب الأكبر بعدما رُبط بعارضة مرتفعة
and hanged!
!وشُنِق
If you're saying someone set that up,
إن كنت تقصد أنّ أحداً نصب ذلك
how in the world did they do it?!
!فكيف له أن يفعلها؟
There were no marks on the beam of him being pulled up, you know!
!لم تكن هناك آثار سحب على العارضة
Of course there aren't any marks.
بالطبع لم تكن هناك آثار
The killer floated directly up to the beam along with the head priest
فالمجرم ارتفع للعارضة مع الراهب الأكبر مباشرةً
and then tied him to it!
!ثمّ ربطه بها
Floated up?!
!ارتفع؟
Don't tell me it was the Kiri Tengu...
لا يُعقل أنّه كان تينغو الضباب
No human could do anything like that...
ولا يمكن لبشريّ فعل ذلك
Hear that sound?
أتسمع هذا الصوت؟
Yes, it's the waterfall.
أجل، صوت الشلّال
Yes. The waterfall that flows directly next to the top window...
صحيح، الشلّال الذي ينهمر بجوار النافذة العلوية مباشرةً
Wouldn't it be possible to float to the ceiling
ألن يكون ممكناً الارتفاع للسقف
if you diverted the waterfall through the window
إذا أعدت توجيه الشلّال عبر النافذة
and filled the entire room with water?
وملأت الغرفة بأسرها بالماء؟
Fill this entire room with water?
ملأ هذه الغرفة بالماء؟
You have to be kidding me.
لا بدّ أنّك تمازحني
Both the killer and the victim would be sopping wet,
سيكون القاتل والضحيّة مبللين بالكامل عندها
but there were no signs of wetness on the body at all!
ولم تكن هناك أيّ آثار بلل على الجثّة
An inflatable raft, Inspector.
طوف قابل للنفخ حضرة المفتّش
An inflatable raft?
طـ-طوف قابل للنفخ؟
Kannen-san.
كانّين-سان
You said there was an inflatable raft in the temple, correct?
قلتَ أنّه يوجد طوف قابل للنفخ في هذا المعبد، صحيح؟
Yes.
أ-أجل
If the body was in the raft and covered with a plastic sheet or something,
إن كانت الجثّة على الطوف ويغطيها غطاء بلاستيكيّ أو ما شابه
then it could have made it to the top without getting wet.
فيمكنها أن تصل السقف دون أن تتبلل
But the waterfall and the window are too far apart!
!لكنّ الشلال والنافذة متباعدان
No matter how well things might fit,
مهما تلاءمت لك الأمور
nobody could divert the water into the room...
لا يمكن أن تعيد توجيه الماء للغرفة
The drainboard.
لوح تصريف
The killer covered the gaps in the drainboard with tape, flipped it over,
غطّى القاتل الفجوات في لوح التصريف بشريط لاصق وقلبه
and then redirected the waterfall through the window.
ثمّ أعاد توجيه الشلال عبر النافذة
As proof of this, the cut on the drainboard is warped.
ودليلاً على ذلك، كان أثر القطع على لوح التصريف معوجاً
It was cut to make it short enough to fit...
...قُطع ليكون قصيراً ما يكفي ليتّسع
And there are cherry blossom petals stuck to the board
كما هناك بتلات أزهار كرز ملتصقة باللوح
in the spots where the tape would have been...
في المواضع التي كان سيكون مكانها الشريط اللاصق
The same petals that are carried down the waterfall
نفس البتلات التي يأخذها الشلّال
from the trees at the top of the mountain.
من الأشجار أعلى الجبل
And it wasn't just the drainboard that had flower petals stuck to it.
ولم يكن لوح التصريف وحده ما كانت عالقةً به البتلات
They should fall down to your feet soon, Inspector.
يُفترض أن تسقط عند قدميك قريباً حضرة المفتّش
The petals that got stuck to the side of the wall
البتلة التي التصقت بجانب الحائط
when the killer removed the water, that is!
!بعدما أخرج القاتل الماء
In other words, after killing the head priest,
أي أنّه بعد قتله للكاهن الأكبر
the killer carried the body into this room,
نقل الجثّة لهذه الغرفة
put it into the inflatable raft,
وضعها على طوف قابل للنفخ
covered the inner doorframe with tape,
وغطّى إطار الباب الداخليّ بشريط لاصق
and temporarily left the room through the sliding panel.
ثمّ غادر الغرفة مؤقتاً عبر النافذة الصغيرة
Then the killer began filling the room with water
ثمّ بدأ بملء الغرفة بالماء من نافذة
from the 2nd floor window using the method I just illustrated,
الطابق الثاني باستعمال الطريقة التي وضّحتها
quickly returned to the 1st floor,
وعاد للطابق الأوّل سريعاً
entered through the sliding panel,
ثمّ دخل من النافذة الصغيرة
and then covered it with tape too.
وغطّاها بشريط لاصق أيضاً
Otherwise, the water would leak out through the panel.
وإلّا كان الماء ليتسرّب من الحواف
After that, while taking great care not to get the body wet,
،بعدها، مع حرصه على ألّا تتبلل الجثة
all the killer had to do was wait for the room to fill up.
كلّ ما كان عليه هو انتظار امتلاء الغرفة بالماء
After the room filled up enough, the killer arrived at the beam,
وبعد امتلائها، وصل القاتل للعارضة
tied the corpse to it,
ربط الجثّة بها
and then escaped out the top window.
ثمّ هرب من النافذة العلوية
But how did the killer get rid of the water?
لكن كيف أخرج القاتل الماء؟
By breaking the sliding panel with the axe
بتحطّيم النافذة الصغيرة بالفأس
that was left at the scene of the crime.
الذي كان في مسرح الجريمة
Yes. This room's floor is about 4.5 tatami in area
أجل، مساحة هذه الغرفة تُعادل 4.5 تاتامي تقريباً
and the walls are about 10 meters high,
والحائط بارتفاع 10 أمتار
so its volume is 2.7 meters by 2.7 meters by 10 meters,
لذا يكون الحجم 2.7 م ضرب 2.7 م ضرب 10 م
or 72.9 meters cubed.
أي 72.9 متر مكعّب
The specific gravity of water is 1,
الكثافة النسبية للماء هي 1
so the weight of all the water in the filled room would be 72.9 tons.
لذا وزن كلّ الماء في الغرفة الممتلئة سيكون 72.9 طنّاً
If you used an axe to break a panel at the bottom of a room
إذا استعملت فأساً لتحطيم نافذة في أسفل غرفة تحوي
with that much water,
ذاك القدر من الماء
you know what would happen.
تعرفون ما سيحصل
The cracked panel would fly out under 9.8 x 10 to the 4th Pascals of pressure!
ستُقذف النافذة المتصدّعة تحت ضغط يُعادل 9.8 ضرب 10 مرفوعة لـ 4 باسكال
Under the immense strength of the water,
،وبقوّة تيّار الماء الهائل
more and more of the wall would erode off, creating a gaping hole!
!سيتحطم المزيد من الحائط فتُفتح فجوة كبيرة
9.8 x 10 to the 4th Pascals?
تسعة فاصلة ثمانية ضرب 10 مرفوعة لـ 4 باسكال؟
A huge amount of power-- like getting run over by a truck.
إنّه قدر هائل من القوّة، كدهس شاحنة لك
I see!
فهمت
So that's why there's no debris even though the hole is so big!
لذا لم تكن هناك بقايا حطام رغم تشكّل فجوة بهذا الحجم
Conan found a fragment of the wall in the woods below the temple.
وجد كونان جزءاً من البقايا في الغابة تحت المعبد
He did?
كونان-كن؟
Here you go, Inspector!
هاك سيّدي المفتش
I see.
فهمت
A piece of the sliding panel with tape on it.
قطعة من النافذة الصغيرة بشريط لاصق
But who in the world would do such a thing?!
لكن من قد يُقدم على شيء كهذا؟
It would take less than ten seconds for the water to exit the room,
سيحتاج خروج الماء من الغرفة أقل من 10 ثوان
but filling the room, that's a whole different story.
لكن ملء الغرفة موضوع مختلف
The amount of water entering from the drainboard
مقدار الماء الذي دخل عبر لوح التصريف
is five to six times as much as through a faucet.
يُعادل 5 إلى 6 أضعاف ماء الصنبور
If we estimate that it filled up 10 cubic meters per hour,
إذا افترضنا أنّه ملأ 10 أمتار مكعّبة في الساعة
it would take seven hours to completely fill this room!
ستحتاج 7 ساعات لملء الغرفة التي حجمها 72.9 طنّاً بأسرها
The head priest's estimated time of death
وقت موت الراهب الأكبر المقدّر
was between 10:00 pm and 12:00 am last night.
هو بين العاشرة ليلاً لمنتصف ليل البارحة
And it was 8:00 am when his body was discovered.
وعُثر على جثّته في الثامنة صباحاً
Even if you deduct the time to set up the trick
حتى إذا اقتطعت زمن إعداد الحيلة
and the time needed to release the water and dry the room
والوقت المطلوب لإخراج الماء وجفاف الغرفة
the killer must have been in this room between midnight and 6:00 am!
كان القاتل في هذه الغرفة بالتأكيد !بين منتصف الليل حتّى السادسة صباحاً
What does that have to do with the killer?
ما علاقة ذاك بالقاتل؟
Shunen-san.
شونين-سان
You said you were reading a book in your room
قلتَ أنّك كنت تقرأ في غرفتك
until 3:00 am last night, correct?
حتّى الثالثة من صباح البارحة، صحيح؟
If so, then you too should've heard a certain someone scream
كان يُفترض أنّك سمعت إذاً صرخة أحدهم ...عند دورة المياه
when they saw the Tengu mask from the bathroom!
عندما أفزعه قناع تينغو الضباب
Who screamed?!
من كان؟
Answer me!
!أجبني
Shunen...
...شـ-شونين
Of course I heard Ran-san scream!
!سـ-سمعته بالطبع
It caught me by surprise!
أفزعتني
I can't blame her for being scared, though...
...لا يمكنني لومها لأنّها سريعة الخوف، لكن
Shunen! Did you--
...شونين! أنت
Shunen-san.
شونين-سان
It wasn't Ran who screamed.
لم تكن ران من صرخ وقتها
It was me!
كان أنا
But it's not your fault you didn't hear me.
لكن لا عجب لعدم سماعك لي
You were in here all night,
فقد كنت هنا طوال الليل
surrounded by the thunderous roar of the water, after all.
وهدير الماء يتردد في أذنيك
But his testimony won't hold as evidence, Mori-kun!
!لكن لن تثبت هذه الشهادة كدليل يا موري-كن
If it's undeniable proof that you want,
إذا كنت تريد دليلاً دامغاً
then you're holding it right now, Inspector.
فهو بيدك الآن حضرة المفتّش
This piece of wood?
قطعة الخشب هذه؟
By wiping the room off later, the killer could destroy the evidence,
تمكّن القاتل من إزالة الدليل عبر مسح الماء في الغرفة لاحقاً
but he couldn't do that with that piece of wood
لكنه لم يستطع مسح قطعة الخشب هذه
since it went flying off.
بما أنّ التيّار قذفها
Yes.
صحيح
That is the only thing the killer failed to recover!
إنّها الشيء الوحيد الذي فشل القاتل في استعادته
I would bet my life as a detective
أراهن بحياتي كمتحرٍّ
that they're still on the tape stuck to that board...
...أنّها لا تزال على الشريط اللاصق على القطعة
Shunen-san. I'm referring to your fingerprints!
شونين-سان، أقصد بصماتك
But Shunen came to this temple a year ago!
!لكن شونين أتى لهذا المعبد قبل عام
If this is the same trick as the one two years ago,
إن كانت نفس حيلة الحادثة قبل عامين
then the same person did it!
فيُفترض أنّ الشخص نفسه
Shunen couldn't have done it!
!يستحيل أنّه كان شونين
The incident two years ago was probably the head priest's doing,
الحادثة قبل عامين كانت من تدبير الراهب الأكبر غالباً
using the exact same trick as this time.
باستعمال هذه الحيلة تماماً
The cut on the drainboard was old,
كان أثر القطع على لوح التصريف قديماً
and he was the one most afraid to talk about the incident.
وكان أكثر من يخشى الكلام عن الحادثة
And if my instincts are correct,
وإذا أصاب حدسي
the late Chunen-san and Shunen-san were probably brothers!
فتشونين-سان المقتول قبل عامين وشونين-سان شقيقان على الأغلب
It's true.
صحيح
Chunen was my genuine blood brother.
كان تشونين شقيقي بالدم
It was only natural that no one realized it...
من الطبيعيّ أن أحداً لم يدرك
To hide my origin, I came as a priest-in-training
أتيت كراهب قيد التمرين لإخفاء خلفيتي التاريخية
after studying at a distantly-related temple first.
بعد دراستي في معبد بعيد الصلة أوّلاً
was to find out the truth behind my brother's death
هو معرفة حقيقة موت أخي بالطبع
and find the real culprit!
وإيجاد الفاعل الحقيقيّ
I scoured the temple for half a year.
فتّشتُ المعبد لنصف عام
I had the trick figured out, but I didn't know who did it.
اكتشفتُ الحيلة، لكني لم أعرف الفاعل
Nobody wanted to talk about the incident, you see.
فلم يرد أحد الكلام عن الحادثة
But I realized it when you came yesterday, Detective.
لكنّي أدركت عندما أتيتَ بالأمس حضرة المتحرّي
Afterwards, I went to his room and found him drinking his night sake.
ذهبتُ بعدها لغرفته، ووجدته منكبّاً على شرابه الليلي
When I pressed the issue, he told me about all sorts of things!
فضغطتُ عليه وأخبرني بكلّ شيء
He had no idea I was actually Chunen's younger brother!
لم يعلم أنّي أخو تشونين الأصغر
The reason he killed my brother
سبب قتله لأخي
was because he didn't want him to take his granddaughter Kikuno-san,
هو أنّه لم يرده أن يأخذ حفيدته كيكونو-سان
who was to marry a successor to a big temple.
التي كان يُفترض أن تتزوّج خليفة معبد كبير
Kikuno-san and my brother supposedly even agreed to elope together,
...اتّفق أخي مع كيكونو-سان على الفرار معاً وفقما يبدو
but that doesn't matter now...
لكنّ ذلك لا يهم الآن
Anyway, when I asked the head priest to give himself up, he--
بأيّ حال، عندما طلبتُ من الراهب الأكبر ...تسليم نفسه، قال
There's no evidence left from what happened two years ago anyway!
لم يبق دليل من الحادثة قبل عامين بأيّ حال
Besides, this temple has gained prestige thanks to that incident!
كما أنّ هذا المعبد اكتسب سمعةً بسببها
It's known as the temple where the Kiri Tengu appears!
!أصبح يُعرف بمعبد ظهور تينغو الضباب
When he said that, I lost control of myself
فقدتُ السيطرة على أعصابي عندما قال ذلك
and strangled him to death with a belt in the room!
وخنقته للموت بحزام في الغرفة
Yes. Just like he strangled my brother two years ago...
أجل، كما خنق أخي قبل عامين
...with him on my back,
خنقته مسنداً ظهري
to leave marks to make it look like a hanging suicide...
لترك آثار تجعله يبدو انتحاراً بالشنق
With his corpse at my feet, I had no other choice.
لم يكن لديّ خيار آخر بوجود الجثّة بين قدميّ
I would have to use the same trick he used two years ago
كان عليّ استعمال نفس حيلته قبل عامين
to hide the truth...
لإخفاء الحقيقة
It's too bad you didn't visit this temple two years ago, Detective.
من المؤسف أنّك لم تزر المعبد قبل عامين حضرة المتحرّي
If you had, I would probably be...
...لو فعلت، غالباً لكنتُ
You surprise me every single time, Mori-kun!
!تفاجئني كلّ مرة يا موري-كن
Yeah, like when you talked about Pascals or something...
أجل، عندما تكلّمت يا أبي ...عن باسكال وما شابه
"Pascals"?
باسكال؟
What they mean is--
...ذلك
"Oscar" is from Takarazuka...
...أوسكار من تاكارازوكا
"Rascal" is a kind of raccoon...
...راسكال هو أحد أنواع الراكون
What's a Pascal?!
ما باسكال بالضبط؟
You dummy, that's "Telepal"!
!أحمق، تلك تيليبال
And you only got the "al" right!
!كما أصبت في جزء "ال" فقط
The weapon was a potted plant.
كان السلاح أصيص أزهار
You're always getting into trouble.
دائماً أنت
Stop interfering with the investigation.
!كفّ عن التدخل في التحقيق
The issue is
المشكلة الأولى هي أنت يا دوباشي-سان
Looks like something hard struck it from below.
...يبدو أنّ شيئاً صلباً أصابه من الأسفل
They must be the culprit.
لا يمكن أن يكون المجرم سوى ذاك الشخص
The next episode of Conan is
الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Mystery Weapon Murder!"
قضيّة سلاح جريمة القتل الغامض
Next Conan's hint!
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Bird!
طير صغير
The new school term starts next episode! [I checked when this episode originally aired, and the date makes sense. It was April 7.]
!مع الحلقة القادمة يبدأ فصلٌ جديد
Don't be late!
!لا تتأخّروا